<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Management on Flinker | Building Digital Twins in Microsoft 365</title><link>https://flinker.app/categories/data-management/</link><description>Recent content in Data Management on Flinker | Building Digital Twins in Microsoft 365</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flinker.app/categories/data-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leveraging SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE) for Large Construction Projects</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-construction-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-construction-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Leveraging SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE) for Large Construction Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Large-scale construction projects often grapple with fragmented data, misaligned communications, and inefficient workflows. A Common Data Environment (CDE) addresses these challenges by providing a centralized platform to manage, collaborate on, and leverage critical project data throughout a project&amp;rsquo;s lifecycle. SharePoint, deeply integrated within Microsoft 365, emerges as a powerful, secure, and scalable solution ideal for managing complex construction data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Real-World Success Stories: Why Leading Construction Firms Choose SharePoint as Their CDE</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-success-stories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-success-stories/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://flinker.app/assets-flinker/images/blog/blog-img-3-1.png" alt="SharePoint Common Data Environment in Construction">&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="how-leading-construction-companies-use-sharepoint-as-a-common-data-environment-cde">How Leading Construction Companies Use SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE)&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In today’s construction industry, success depends on managing data effectively across global teams, complex projects, and tight deadlines. Traditional tools like spreadsheets, shared drives, and siloed platforms are no longer enough. That’s why many leading construction firms are adopting &lt;strong>SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE)&lt;/strong> — transforming scattered information into streamlined, collaborative, and secure workflows.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>