<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Digital Transformation on Flinker | The built-environment layer for Microsoft 365</title><link>https://flinker.app/tags/digital-transformation/</link><description>Recent content in Digital Transformation on Flinker | The built-environment layer for Microsoft 365</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flinker.app/tags/digital-transformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ISO 19650 on SharePoint: Why a Policy-Driven App Beats Power Automate-Only</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/iso19650-sharepoint-policy-driven-vs-power-automate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/iso19650-sharepoint-policy-driven-vs-power-automate/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="iso-19650-on-sharepoint-why-a-policy-driven-app-beats-a-power-automate-only-approach">ISO 19650 on SharePoint: Why a Policy-Driven App Beats a &amp;ldquo;Power Automate-Only&amp;rdquo; Approach&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Many construction and infrastructure organizations want an ISO 19650–aligned Common Data Environment (CDE) while keeping data inside Microsoft 365. SharePoint provides the underlying document management platform, and Power Automate is often used to stitch processes together. In practice, however, an ISO 19650 CDE requires more than automation steps: it requires governance, repeatability, enforceable rules, and predictable user experience at scale.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ISO 19650 and SharePoint: Making Your Project Data Room Compliant</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/iso19650-sharepoint-cde/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/iso19650-sharepoint-cde/</guid><description>&lt;p>ISO 19650 is becoming a baseline requirement in construction and infrastructure contracts. Many organizations already have Microsoft 365 and SharePoint in place—often underutilized for project document control. The question: can SharePoint serve as a fully ISO 19650-compliant Common Data Environment (CDE)?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes—but only with the right controls, workflows, and governance layered on top. Native SharePoint provides foundational capabilities but lacks the discipline ISO 19650 demands.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-is-iso-19650">What is ISO 19650?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>ISO 19650 is the international standard (originating from the UK&amp;rsquo;s PAS/BS 1192 lineage) for information management using BIM across the lifecycle of a built asset. It covers how information is exchanged, approved, stored, and retrieved, and defines the Common Data Environment (CDE)—the single agreed source of truth for all project information.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leveraging SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE) for Large Construction Projects</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-construction-projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-construction-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>A Common Data Environment (CDE) centralizes project documents, drawings, models, and coordination data in a single accessible location. For organizations using Microsoft 365, SharePoint provides the underlying infrastructure: document libraries, metadata, version control, and permissions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This guide covers the technical implementation of SharePoint as a CDE for construction projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sharepoint-capabilities-relevant-to-cde">SharePoint capabilities relevant to CDE&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="data-storage-and-organization">Data storage and organization&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>SharePoint document libraries support:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Folder hierarchies&lt;/strong> for organizing by discipline, zone, or work package&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Metadata columns&lt;/strong> for classification (document type, status, revision, originator)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Content types&lt;/strong> for applying consistent metadata schemas across libraries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Views&lt;/strong> for filtering and sorting based on metadata values&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="version-control">Version control&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Automatic version history with configurable major/minor versioning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check-in/check-out to prevent concurrent editing conflicts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Version comments and restore capability&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="permissions-and-access">Permissions and access&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Site-level, library-level, folder-level, and item-level permissions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>SharePoint groups for role-based access (e.g., design team, contractor, client)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>External sharing with configurable link expiration and password protection&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conditional access policies through Azure AD&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="integration-with-microsoft-365">Integration with Microsoft 365&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Teams&lt;/strong>: Channels linked to SharePoint folders for collaboration context&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Power BI&lt;/strong>: Reports and dashboards connected to SharePoint lists and libraries&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Power Automate&lt;/strong>: Workflow automation for notifications, approvals, metadata updates&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Outlook&lt;/strong>: Email alerts and document sharing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="example-cde-folder-structure">Example CDE folder structure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A typical SharePoint CDE for construction might use this hierarchy:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How Leading Construction Companies Use SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE)</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-success-stories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-success-stories/</guid><description>&lt;p>Construction projects generate large volumes of documents, drawings, models, and coordination data. Traditional tools—shared drives, email attachments, siloed platforms—create fragmentation that leads to version conflicts, access issues, and coordination errors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many construction firms already have Microsoft 365 licenses. SharePoint, as part of that ecosystem, provides a foundation for a Common Data Environment (CDE): centralized storage, version control, granular permissions, and integration with Teams, Power BI, and other Microsoft tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-sharepoint-as-a-cde">Why SharePoint as a CDE?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>SharePoint offers several characteristics relevant to construction project data management:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visualize BIM Models in Power BI with Flinker's 3D Viewer</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/visualize-bim-in-power-bi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/visualize-bim-in-power-bi/</guid><description>&lt;p>IFC (Industry Foundation Classes) is the standard for sharing BIM data across platforms in the AECO industry. But when it&amp;rsquo;s time to present models in Power BI, the geometry is missing—just numbers, no visual context. Power BI doesn&amp;rsquo;t natively support IFC files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Flinker&amp;rsquo;s 3D IFC Viewer embeds IFC models directly into Power BI reports:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Interactive 3D views alongside live data, charts, and KPIs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No plugins, no extra licenses, no data uploads&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="why-embed-ifc-in-power-bi">Why embed IFC in Power BI?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>BIM models contain spatial and attribute data that becomes more valuable when linked to business metrics. Without visual context, stakeholders review disconnected tools or rely on screen-sharing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>