<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AECO Industry on Flinker | Building Digital Twins in Microsoft 365</title><link>https://flinker.app/tags/aeco-industry/</link><description>Recent content in AECO Industry on Flinker | Building Digital Twins in Microsoft 365</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flinker.app/tags/aeco-industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leveraging SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE) for Large Construction Projects</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-construction-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-construction-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Leveraging SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE) for Large Construction Projects&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Large-scale construction projects often grapple with fragmented data, misaligned communications, and inefficient workflows. A Common Data Environment (CDE) addresses these challenges by providing a centralized platform to manage, collaborate on, and leverage critical project data throughout a project&amp;rsquo;s lifecycle. SharePoint, deeply integrated within Microsoft 365, emerges as a powerful, secure, and scalable solution ideal for managing complex construction data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Real-World Success Stories: Why Leading Construction Firms Choose SharePoint as Their CDE</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-success-stories/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-success-stories/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Real-World Success Stories: Why Leading Construction Firms Choose SharePoint as Their CDE&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Implementing a Common Data Environment (CDE) like SharePoint can dramatically transform construction project management. Here, we explore practical examples from industry leaders, highlight specific metrics, and detail how SharePoint compares favorably against traditional CDE solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="real-world-use-cases">Real-World Use Cases&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="case-study-1-major-infrastructure-project">Case Study 1: Major Infrastructure Project&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A European infrastructure firm adopted SharePoint as their central repository for BIM models, project documentation, and collaborative workflows. By centralizing IFC files and integrating with Microsoft Teams and Power BI, they significantly reduced coordination errors by 25%, improved document retrieval speeds by 30%, and boosted overall project productivity by over 20%.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visualize BIM Models in Power BI with Flinker's 3D Viewer</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/visualize-bim-in-power-bi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/visualize-bim-in-power-bi/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="visualize-bim-models-in-power-bi-using-flinkers-3d-viewer">Visualize BIM Models in Power BI using Flinker&amp;rsquo;s 3D Viewer&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="power-bi-bim-integration">Power BI BIM Integration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Integrate and interact with IFC models within your dashboards for enhanced project insights without using any extra software.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the Architecture, Engineering, Construction, and Operations (AECO) industry, &lt;strong>IFC (Industry Foundation Classes)&lt;/strong> has become the standard for sharing Building Information Modeling (BIM) data across platforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Professionals build rich 3D models, but when it’s time to present them in Power BI, something’s missing: the model itself. No geometry, no visual context, just numbers. Power BI doesn’t natively support IFC.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>