<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CDE on Flinker | Building Digital Twins in Microsoft 365</title><link>https://flinker.app/tags/cde/</link><description>Recent content in CDE on Flinker | Building Digital Twins in Microsoft 365</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flinker.app/tags/cde/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ISO 19650 and SharePoint: Making Your Project Data Room Compliant</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/iso19650-sharepoint-cde/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/iso19650-sharepoint-cde/</guid><description>&lt;!-- Body stays markdown below -->
&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In today’s construction and real estate ecosystem, information is as critical as bricks and steel. Projects are becoming more complex, many stakeholders are remote, and expectations for precision, traceability, and accountability are rising. That’s why &lt;strong>ISO 19650&lt;/strong> is fast becoming a mandatory requirement in many contracts and public procurements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet many firms already have Microsoft 365 and &lt;strong>SharePoint&lt;/strong> in place — often under-utilized for project document control. The question is:&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Can SharePoint serve as a fully ISO 19650-compliant Common Data Environment (CDE)?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Leveraging SharePoint as a Common Data Environment (CDE) for Large Construction Projects</title><link>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-construction-projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flinker.app/blog/sharepoint-cde-construction-projects/</guid><description>&lt;p>Large-scale construction projects often grapple with fragmented data, misaligned communications, and inefficient workflows. A Common Data Environment (CDE) addresses these challenges by providing a centralized platform to manage, collaborate on, and leverage critical project data throughout a project&amp;rsquo;s lifecycle. SharePoint, deeply integrated within Microsoft 365, emerges as a powerful, secure, and scalable solution ideal for managing complex construction data.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-choose-sharepoint-as-your-cde">Why Choose SharePoint as Your CDE?&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="1-data-sovereignty-and-security">1. Data Sovereignty and Security&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>SharePoint ensures your project data stays securely within your own Microsoft environment, enhancing data sovereignty and compliance. This reduces dependency on external third-party cloud solutions, ensuring maximum data control and security.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>